zach chan **UX** Designer

education

Simon Fraser University 2013 - 2020 (ongoing)

B/Sc Interactive Arts & Technology Minor Beedie School of Business w/ Co-operative Education

skills

Design Research + Ideation Prototyping + User Testing Wireframing + 3D Modelling Motion Design + Videography Brand + Market Research + **Business Analysis**

tools

Adobe Creative Suite AxureRP + Figma Maya + Unity HTML5 + CSS3 + Javascript Git + PHP + SQL

extra zach

(interests)





Drawing



Hiking



Nerdiness

about me

I'm a **UX designer** specializing in web, mobile, and 3D space environments. My background is in **front-end web development** but I love to continuously learn and find inspiration in new technologies. I'm a visual thinker who loves collaborating and understanding the lenses of my peers and users so that I can execute ideas in delightful, efficient solutions.

experience

UX Design Intern

BlackBerry Ltd. || Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

I worked on the BlackBerry Hub+ Android application suite and BlackBerry Secure Android OS. During my time here I collaborated with project managers, developers, and other designers to solve complex interface and product experience problems.

- Designed + shared UI/UX through sketches, wireframes, and technical specs
- Conducted user research, market research, and usablity testing
- Created icons and animated UI interactions
- Designed internal asset manager library to improve workflow

Web Designer/Developer

Alvis Tsui (FSS) Inc. | May 2017 - Dec. 2017

I created web application forms and a searchable database of FSS' school information to extend their services beyond telephone and in-office mediums. I controlled the full end-to-end design and development of this project.

- Built interactive wireframes in Axure RP
- Programmed responsive web pages with PHP, JavaScript, and PHPMailer
- Designed database architecture and built database with SQL
- Created user manual to handoff completed tool to FSS employees

projects

User Research & UX Design

Fit First Run Club | May 2017 - Aug. 2017

In a team of 3, I conducted extensive user research that led to designing a digital community interface to set and track collaborative running goals so that the connectivity and motivation of members of the running club would be enhanced. After the design phase, I filmed, animated and edited a summative project showcase video.

User Research & App Design

DIS • COVERED Mobile App || Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2018

In a team of 4, I researched and designed a mobile application with the goal of aiding refugees and immigrants new to Canada who are facing the daunting task of discovering and integrating into their new community. I did background research and designed micro-interactions in the final prototype.